Inventory of the Eric Chenoweth papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Eric Chenoweth papers
1981-2015
2014C32
Hoover Institution Archives
95 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (39.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, grant proposals, conference proceedings, press releases, bulletins, financial records, lists, printed matter, photographs, and videorecordings relating to activities of the Committee in Support of Solidarity in the United States, and to human rights conditions in Poland; and to activities of the Institute for Democracy in Eastern Europe in promoting democracy in Eastern Europe. Includes records of these organizations.
Chenoweth, Eric.
Committee in Support of Solidarity (New York, N.Y.).
Institute for Democracy in Eastern Europe.
Access
Boxes 30-37, 71-73, and 80-87 are closed. The rest of the collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2014.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Eric Chenoweth served as executive director for the Committee in Support of Solidarity (CSS) from 1981 to 1988. The CSS was created by both Irena Lasota and Chenoweth, who both later organized the Institute for Democracy in Eastern Europe. Later, Chenoweth served as co-director for the Institute for Democracy in Eastern Europe.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, grant proposals, conference proceedings, press releases, bulletins, financial records, lists, printed matter, photographs, and videorecordings relating to activities of the Committee in Support of Solidarity in the United States, and to human rights conditions in Poland; and to activities of the Institute for Democracy in Eastern Europe in promoting democracy in Eastern Europe. Includes records of these organizations.
NSZZ "Solidarność" (Labor organization); Poland--History--1980-1989.; Civil rights--Poland.; Democracy.; Poland--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Poland.; Europe, Eastern--Politics and government--1989-
- Committee in Support of Solidarity (CSS) activities, six-months' report, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- CSS annual reports with attachments, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- CSS annual reports and HR reports, responses and correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- CSS articles, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- CSS articles, Waclaw Adamczak (IMF/WSJ), 1985 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- CSS activities, publications, The Interrogation - translated by J. Warman, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- CSS activities, letters to the editor, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- E. Chenoweth, speeches, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- CSS Board of Directors, minutes, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 1: 9)
- CSS corporate records, IRS application/acceptance, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 1: 10)
- CSS sponsors, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes correspondence, acceptances, and lists.
- AFL-CIO correspondence, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  David Dorn, AFT.
- Correspondence (sanctions), 1983 (Box-folder 1: 13)
- Correspondence, human rights, military penal camps, 1983 (Box-folder 1: 14)
- Correspondence, lifting of martial law, 1983 August (Box-folder 1: 15)
- Correspondence, CSS human rights violations report, 1985 March (Box-folder 1: 16)
- Correspondence, INTL Confederation of Free Trade Unions, 1986 (Box-folder 1: 17)
- Correspondence, CSS prisoners list, 1984 July (Box-folder 1: 18)
- Outgoing correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 1: 19)
- Correspondence, Radio Free Europe, 1986 August (Box-folder 1: 20)
  Including that of Zdzislaw Najder.
- Correspondence, human rights publications, report on torture, 1987 (Box-folder 1: 21)
- Correspondence, CSS activities, letter and lists, report repression, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 1: 22)
- Correspondence, lobbying efforts, undated (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Miscellaneous mailing lists, undated (Box-folder 2: 2)
- CSS mailing lists, 1982 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  Break in numbering sequence 1.26-1.29.
- CSS fundraising, advertisements, letters, 1982 April (Box-folder 2: 4)
- CSS fundraising, Barry Farber reception, 1982 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- CSS fundraising, budget, 1982 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- CSS fundraising, grants, individual contributors, 1984 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- CSS fundraising, trade unions, letters and responses, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 2: 8)
- CSS fundraising, trade unions, letters and responses, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- CSS fundraising, grants, Ford Foundation proposals, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- CSS fundraising, grants, Toqueville Institution, undated (Box-folder 2: 11)
- CSS fundraising, grants, Jagiellonian Trust, 1986 (Box-folder 2: 12)
- CSS fundraising, grants, Jurzykowski Foundation, undated (Box-folder 2: 13)
- CSS fundraising, grants, Readers Digest Foundation, undated (Box-folder 2: 14)
- CSS fundraising, grants, Scaife Foundation, 1983 (Box-folder 2: 15)
- CSS fundraising, grants, Wolfenson, James FD, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 2: 16)
- CSS activities, leaflets, postcards, undated (Box-folder 2: 17)
- CSS activities, list of comm in support of Solidarity, undated (Box-folder 2: 18)
- CSS media, media appearances, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 2: 19)
- CSS media, media appearances, 1983 (Box-folder 2: 20)
- CSS propaganda (official), undated (Box-folder 2: 21)
- Office administration, list of publications, CSS, undated (Box-folder 2: 22)
- Polska, komunizm, opozycja - leaflet, 1985 (Box-folder 2: 23)
- Countdown, undated (Box-folder 2: 24)
- CSS postcards, originals, 1982 (Box-folder 2: 25)
- CSS activities, publications, press advisories, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  Out of order.
- CSS (PWTF) Solidarnosc bulletin, world affairs, Malinowski photos, 1981 (Box-folder 3: 2)
- Lists of CSS spokespeople, undated (Box-folder 3: 3)
  Break in numbering sequence 1.53-59
- Sanctions, undated (Box-folder 3: 4)
  Includes miscellaneous research files - CSS and Nowak.
- Sanctions, letter to secretary of state, 1986 December (Box-folder 3: 5)
- Sanctions and government policy, AFL-CIO and CSS testimony, undated (Box-folder 3: 6)
- CSS testimony before CSCE, 1986 February 25 (Box-folder 3: 7)
- "The Importance of Poland," Waliszewski testimony, DNC-RNC, 1984 (Box-folder 3: 8)
- "The Polish Example," statement for Brzezinski, Karpinski, undated (Box-folder 3: 9)
  Break in numbering.
- Kuklinski working file, 1987 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  Interview in Kultura.
- CSS martial law, response to, undated (Box-folder 3: 11)
- CSS martial law, response to, undated (Box-folder 3: 12)
  West Germany, SPD Schmidt.
- CSS martial law, response to, 1982 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  Congress correspondence.
- Proposal for Polish Workers Task Force (PWTF) to Tom Kahn, undated (Box-folder 4: 1)
- PWTF originals, cover letter, speakers list, forms, undated (Box-folder 4: 2)
- PWTF reports of activity, undated (Box-folder 4: 3)
- PWTF proposal, foundations, undated (Box-folder 4: 4)
- PWTF report on Solidarity support campaign, undated (Box-folder 4: 5)
- State of martial law decree, 1981 (Box-folder 4: 6)
- December 19 demonstration, undated (Box-folder 4: 7)
- CSS December 20 minutes, undated (Box-folder 4: 8)
- CSS activities, briefings, packets, appeals, 1981 December - 1982 April (Box-folder 4: 9)
- CSS activities, congressional testimony, 1982 December - February (Box-folder 4: 10)
- CSS briefing packet for UN, 1981 December 28 (Box-folder 4: 11)
- Letter to President Reagan, 1982 January 11 (Box-folder 4: 12)
- CSS demonstration, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 13)
- Committee bios, undated (Box-folder 4: 14)
- Campus lists, undated (Box-folder 4: 15)
- CSS materials, miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 4: 16)
- CSS materials, miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 4: 17)
- CSS activities, description, stated, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 18)
- Violations of human rights in Poland, K. Roth, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 19)
- CSS briefing papers, emergency situations and Poland, 1982 February (Box-folder 4: 20)
- CSS activities, briefings, universities under martial law, 1982 March (Box-folder 4: 21)
- Independent Student Association, undated (Box-folder 4: 22)
- CSS briefing papers prepared for mathematicians, 1982 May (Box-folder 4: 23)
- CSS project of indictment (Brantley), 1982 July (Box-folder 4: 24)
- CSS demonstrations, 1982 August 31 (Box-folder 4: 25)
- CSS fundraising, Wanda Wilkomirska concert, 1982 November 11 (Box-folder 4: 26)
- List of killed, incoming information, 1982 (Box-folder 5: 1)
- "Acta Medica," KOS medical report, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 5: 2)
- CSS report, "Institutionalization of Martial Law,", 1983 January (Box-folder 5: 3)
- CSS report, TKK to CSCE, 1983 March (Box-folder 5: 4)
- CSS report on military camps, 1983 March (Box-folder 5: 5)
- CSS press release, "Edelman Refuses Participation,", 1983 March (Box-folder 5: 6)
- CSS report, "Solidarity and the Situation in Poland", 1983 May (Box-folder 5: 7)
- CSS Helsinki Committee rep. on trade union situation, 1983 June (Box-folder 5: 8)
- CSS report, independent education, 1983 July (Box-folder 5: 9)
- CSS activities, Tyrawska Danuta, case of, 1983 July - August (Box-folder 5: 10)
- Status of political prisoners, 1983 July (Box-folder 5: 11)
- CSS report on lifting of martial law, 1983 August (Box-folder 5: 12)
  Includes Kirkpatrick letter.
- Janusz Onyszkiewicz (mathematician arrested), 1983 July (Box-folder 5: 13)
- Glemp letter to Jaruzelski (re Bank for Farmers), 1983 July (Box-folder 5: 14)
- CSS activities, letter to Perez de Cuellar (re Poland visit), 1984 February (Box-folder 5: 15)
- Helsinki Committee in Poland, special report to UN, 1984 March (Box-folder 5: 16)
- Institute for Nuclear Research, Cultural Revolution, 1983 May-1984 May (Box-folder 5: 17)
- CSS press release, Torun Anti-Solidarity terror, 1984 April (Box-folder 5: 18)
- CSS activities, publications, briefings on asylum, 1984 June (Box-folder 5: 19)
- CSS briefing, political repression, 1984 July (Box-folder 5: 20)
- CSS activities, Helsinki Committee Amnesty in the PRC, 1984 September (Box-folder 5: 21)
- CSS statement, "Who Killed Father Popieluszko,", 1984 October (Box-folder 5: 22)
- CSS activities, briefing, the situation in Poland, 1984 November (Box-folder 5: 23)
- Human rights report, press release, 1985 March (Box-folder 5: 24)
- CSS activities, Abrams letter, critique of HR bureau report, 1985 March (Box-folder 5: 25)
- Reports on higher education (folders A-E), 1985-1986 (Box-folder 5: 26)
- Letter to Helsinki Committee, 1985 July 16 (Box-folder 6: 1)
- Helsinki Committee report, 1986 March (Box-folder 6: 2)
- CSS activities, briefing for Mayor Koch, 1987 January 20 (Box-folder 6: 3)
- CSS activities, briefing for Hoyer, 1987 August 20 (Box-folder 6: 4)
- Aid to families of political prisoners, AFT Program, 1986 September (Box-folder 6: 5)
- Aid to families of political prisoners, lists, undated (Box-folder 6: 6)
- Political prisoners, case file, Czeslaw Bielecki, 1986 March (Box-folder 6: 7)
- Political prisoners, case file, Jan Borowiec, 1986 April (Box-folder 6: 8)
- Political prisoners, case file, Wladyslaw Frasyniuk, 1986 May (Box-folder 6: 9)
- Political prisoners, case file, Bogdan Borusewicz, 1986 October (Box-folder 6: 10)
- Press briefing, Czeslaw Bielecki, 1988 May (Box-folder 6: 11)
- Political prisoners, incoming information, working file, undated (Box-folder 6: 12)
- Underground Society, Kulerski, 1987 (Box-folder 6: 13)
- Biuletyn Informacyjny 1-58, CSS archives, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 7: 1)
- Biuletyn Informacyjny 59-70, CSS archives, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 7: 2)
- Solidarnosc Bulletin, CSS archives, undated (Box-folder 7: 3)
- CSS Report, Nos. 1-50 (partial), undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
- CSS Special Reports, Nos. 1-2, full, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 8: 1)
- "Acta Medica," KOS medical report, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 8: 2)
- Helsinki Committee report on situation of trade unions, ILO, undated (Box-folder 8: 3)
- Report to UN Commission, Helsinki Committee, 1984 March (Box-folder 8: 4)
- CSS partial list of uncensored periodicals, 1984 March (Box-folder 8: 5)
- CSS report, "Violations Continue,", 1984 March (Box-folder 8: 6)
- Political repression and Imprisonment in Poland (partial), 1983-1984 (Box-folder 8: 7)
- CSS report on human rights violations (partial), 1984-1985 (Box-folder 8: 8)
- Helsinki Committee, third report on human and civil rights, 1984 January - September (Box-folder 8: 9)
- Helsinki Committee, fourth report on human and civil rights (partial), 1984-1985 (Box-folder 9: 1)
- Helsinki Committee, report on torture and the use of force, special report (partial), 1985 (Box-folder 9: 2)
- CSS use of political imprisonment in PRL, 1984 August - 1985 August (Box-folder 9: 2)
- CSS use of political imprisonment in PRL, 1985 August - 1986 July (Box-folder 9: 3)
- CSS report on the condition of higher education in Poland, 1986 October (Box-folder 9: 4)
- CSS report, repression in Poland, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 9: 5)
- CSS prisoners lists, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 9: 6)
- Solidarity calendar, undated (Box-folder 10: 1)
- Gdańsk 1980: Pictures from a Strike, printed copy, 1981 (Box-folder 10: 2)
- Postcards, undated (Box-folder 10: 3)
- War Against the Nation pamphlet, undated (Box-folder 10: 4)
- Montenegro, RFA, current program and proposal, 2001 (Box-folder 11: 1)
- Kosova fundraising proposal, USAID RFA, 2001 (Box-folder 11: 2)
- EUR/Serbia mission, continuation of Civic Bridges, Serbia, 2001 (Box-folder 11: 3)
- AID 3 proposal, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 11: 4)
- Proposal for continuation of Breaking Barriers, Building Bridges program, 1999 (Box-folder 11: 5)
- Breaking Barriers, Serbia, 1996 (Box-folder 11: 6)
- Partnership in community building, proposal, Serbia, 1996 (Box-folder 11: 7)
- USAID Demnet regional component, NFF-IDEE, 1994 (Box-folder 11: 8)
- Democracy Network Program, Central and Eastern Europe, request for applications, 1994 (Box-folder 11: 9)
- USAID Poland, Freedom House, 1994 (Box-folder 11: 10)
- The Henry M. Jackson Foundation, 1996 (Box-folder 12: 1)
- International Research and Exchanges Board (IREX), 1996-1997 (Box-folder 12: 2)
- The Freedom Forum, 1995 (Box-folder 12: 3)
- The Eurasia Foundation, undated (Box-folder 12: 4)
- Fundraising, general, undated (Box-folder 12: 5)
- USAID, Promedia II, RFA, 1999 (Box-folder 12: 6)
- Final report, audit evaluation and project support fund, 1997 April 21 (Box-folder 12: 7)
- USAID, Demnet II, Bulgaria, 1996 (Box-folder 12: 8)
- USAID unsolicited proposal guidelines, undated (Box-folder 12: 9)
- USAID Incorporating Values Program, 2003 (Box-folder 12: 10)
- IDEE miscellaneous documents, 1993-2002 (Box-folder 13: 1)
- Unlikely donors, undated (Box-folder 13: 2)
- Scaife Foundation, 2000 (Box-folder 13: 3)
- USIP proposal, undated (Box-folder 13: 4)
- The Winston Foundation, 1994 (Box-folder 13: 5)
- John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, 2001 (Box-folder 13: 6)
- Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1995 (Box-folder 13: 7)
- Becoming a Citizen: A Basic Educational Democracy Program for Young People in Serbia, 1998 (Box-folder 14: 1)
- Proposal for Students Union of Serbia (SUS), 2000 (Box-folder 14: 2)
- Kosovo memorandum to NED, 1998 (Box-folder 14: 3)
- Kosovo proposal, Serbia proposal, 1999 (Box-folder 14: 4)
- Promoting democracy in Serbia, 1999 (Box-folder 14: 5)
- "To Support Democratic Forces in Yugoslavia,", 1995 (Box-folder 14: 6)
- Azerbaijan, Belarus, Kyrgyzstan, Mongolia materials, undated (Box-folder 14: 7)
- Who's Who sources, 2002 (Box-folder 14: 8)
- Publications, undated (Box-folder 14: 9)
- NED proposal, 2002 (Box-folder 14: 10)
- Publications, undated (Box-folder 15: 1)
- NED Yugoslavia proposal, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 15: 2)
- Muryadov proposal, 2002 (Box-folder 15: 3)
- Central Asia proposal, 2002 (Box-folder 15: 4)
- Proposal for TOT training in Kosova, 2000 (Box-folder 15: 5)
- SUS proposal, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 15: 6)
- Azeri Young Leaders, Balkan media, 1995 (Box-folder 15: 7)
- Cuban Democracy Dialog project, 1995 July (Box-folder 15: 8)
- Yugoslavia, NED, 1999 (Box-folder 15: 9)
- Democratization in the Muslim World, 2002 April 22 (Box-folder 16: 1)
- Azerbaijan: Democracy, Women's Rights, and Islam, 2002 (Box-folder 16: 2)
- Civic Bridges in Central Asia, 2003 May (Box-folder 16: 3)
  Includes proposal for U.S. Department of State Bureau for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor.
- DRL, Central Asia, 2005 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  Includes proposal.
- China, statement of interest, 2005 (Box-folder 16: 5)
- Central Asia and Uzbekistan, statement of interest, 2006 (Box-folder 16: 6)
- DRL, Belarus, 2006 (Box-folder 16: 7)
- Democratization in Cuba, 2005-2007 (Box-folder 16: 8)
- RFPs '08 announcements, 2008 (Box-folder 16: 9)
- RFP for Cuba, Civic Rights and Labor, 2008 (Box-folder 16: 10)
- Cuba, Civil Society proposal, 2008 (Box-folder 16: 11)
- Central Asia RFP, 2008 (Box-folder 17: 1)
- Belarus, independent media, 2008 (Box-folder 17: 2)
- Cuba, independent media, 2008 (Box-folder 17: 3)
- Cuba, independent media, 2008 (Box-folder 17: 4)
  OSCE meetings.
- Cuba, International Solidarity, 2008 (Box-folder 17: 5)
- Cuba, Civil Society for Amendments, 2009 (Box-folder 17: 6)
- Belarus, Act for Freedom, 2009 (Box-folder 17: 7)
  Continuation of Raise Consciousness program.
- RFP for Muslim world, 2010 (Box-folder 17: 8)
  Azerbaijan education program, Central Asia media advocacy.
- Cuba Civil Society, direct support, Cuba Freedom of Expression, 2010 (Box-folder 17: 9)
- RFPs, PSIs, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 18: 1)
- USIA/ECA, Central and Eastern Europe, Living Together program, 1997 (Box-folder 18: 2)
- Women in the Caucasus (WIC 1), proposal, 1998 (Box-folder 18: 3)
- Women in the Caucasus (WIC 2), proposal, 1999 (Box-folder 18: 4)
- Women in the Caucasus (WIC 3), proposal, 2000 (Box-folder 18: 5)
- WICA, proposal, 2000 (Box-folder 18: 6)
- Azerbaijan media training, 2002 (Box-folder 18: 7)
- Georgian libraries, 2002 (Box-folder 18: 8)
- Ukraine tourism, Lviv/Crimea, 2002 (Box-folder 18: 9)
- Georgia Dialogue for Tolerance, 2003 (Box-folder 19: 1)
- Building Community Connections in Armenia, 2003 (Box-folder 19: 2)
- Kyrgystan program, 2004 (Box-folder 19: 3)
- Armenian Women's Leadership Program, 2004 (Box-folder 19: 4)
- Georgia Media Exchange, 2010 (Box-folder 19: 5)
- CSS East European Democracy project, 1984 (Box-folder 20: 1)
- CSS proposal to Free Trade Union Institute, 1984 (Box-folder 20: 2)
- Independent Publishers Consortium, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  First NED grant to IDEE.
- IDEE/NED grant (Independent Publishers Consortium), 1987-1988 (Box-folder 20: 4)
  Confirmations of assistance and publications (copies).
- Funds for independent publishers, 1989 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  Letter from G. Boguta.
- Funds for independent publishers and other independent publications., 1986 (Box-folder 20: 6)
- Road to Solidarity grant, 1987 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  Book publication in Lithuanian and Serbo-Croatian.
- Independent publishing in Poland and Hungary with supplemental funding, 1988 (Box-folder 20: 8)
- Independent publication, Yugoslavia (Naša Rec), 1988 (Box-folder 20: 9)
- Fund for independent publishers, independent publications in Poland, cultural programs in Poland, 1989 (Box-folder 20: 10)
- Independent publishers in Czechoslovakia, 1989 (Box-folder 21: 1)
- Independent publishers and social and cultural groups in Hungary, 1989 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  Includes Fidesz.
- Independent publications, Yugoslavia (Nasa Rec), 1989 (Box-folder 21: 3)
- Fidesz, support grant (Hungary), 1989 (Box-folder 21: 4)
- NED correspondence from Carl Gershman, 1987 (Box-folder 21: 5)
- Free Trade Union Institute (FTUI), 1984-1995 (Box-folder 21: 6)
  Includes grant proposals, agreements, reports, and correspondence.
- FTUI proposal, 1995 (Box-folder 21: 7)
- OLIN Foundation, 1983-1992 (Box-folder 22: 1)
- The Lynde and Harry Bradley Foundation, 1986-1983 (Box-folder 22: 2)
- German Marshall Fund, 1991 (Box-folder 22: 3)
- Miscellaneous, funded projects, 1988-1996 (Box-folder 22: 4)
- Miscellaneous, unfunded projects, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 22: 5)
- Civic Forum, Czechoslovakia, NED grant, 1990 (Box-folder 23: 1)
- Polish publishers, grant agreement, 1990 (Box-folder 23: 2)
- Koninent (Paris-based Russian language quarterly journal), NED grant, 1990 (Box-folder 23: 3)
- Bulgarian Federation of Independent Student Associations, 1990 (Box-folder 23: 4)
- Civic Forum and other independent groups in Czechoslovakia, 1990 (Box-folder 23: 5)
- Public Against Violence (Slovakia), 1990 (Box-folder 23: 6)
- Romanian student groups, 1990 (Box-folder 23: 7)
- CEE print media project, 1990 (Box-folder 23: 8)
- Naša Rec/Demokratia (Yugoslavia), 1990 (Box-folder 23: 9)
- Archa Publishing House of Bratislava (Slovakia), 1991 (Box-folder 23: 10)
- Polish Independent Students' Association (NZS), 1991 (Box-folder 23: 11)
- Free Latvians ( Baltic Times), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 23: 12)
- The Romanian Independent Society for Human Rights (SIRDO/LADO), 1992-1994 (Box-folder 23: 13)
- Publishing civic organization in Romania, Inter-Ethnic Minority Program, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 24: 1)
- Publishing civic organization in Romania, Inter-Ethnic Minority Program, attachments, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 24: 2)
- Humanitas conference (Romania), 1992 (Box-folder 24: 3)
- Svoboda (newspaper), Belarus, 1993 (Box-folder 24: 4)
- Proposals submitted to IDEE, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 24: 5)
- NED-IDEE materials, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 25: 1)
  Includes miscellaneous proposals, reports, and correspondence.
- NED-IDEE audit correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 25: 2)
- Evaluation of selected programs, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 25: 3)
- Special Report: "25 Years After 1989,", 2015 (Box-folder 25: 4)
- Special Issue: "25 Years After 1989,", 2015 (Box-folder 25: 5)
- Centers for Pluralism in Eastern Europe, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  Includes initial grant.
- Centers for Pluralism in Eastern Europe continuation grant, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 26: 2)
- Centers for Pluralism, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 26: 3)
  Includes final report.
- Centers for Pluralism sample publications and grantee reports, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 26: 4)
- Centers for Pluralism in Eastern Europe continuation grant, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 27: 1)
- Centers for Pluralism subgrantee files and reports, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 27: 2)
- Centers for Pluralism, 5th meeting (Bratislava, Slovakia), 1995 (Box-folder 27: 3)
- Centers for Pluralism, 6th meeting (Tirgu Mures, Romania), 1995 (Box-folder 27: 4)
- Centers for Pluralism, 3rd meeting (Budapest, Hungary), 1994 (Box-folder 27: 5)
- Centers for Pluralism, 7th meeting (Warsaw, Poland), 1996 (Box-folder 27: 6)
- Centers for Pluralism, 8th meeting (Eupatoria, Crimea), 1995 (Box-folder 27: 7)
- Network of Independent Journalists, 4th meeting (Sofia, Bulgaria), 1996 (Box-folder 28: 1)
- Centers for Pluralism, 9th meeting (Baku, Azerbaijan), 1997 (Box-folder 28: 2)
- Centers for Pluralism, 10th meeting (Tuzla, Bosnia i Hercegovina), 1997 (Box-folder 28: 3)
- Centers for Pluralism, 11th meeting (Warsaw, Poland), 1998 (Box-folder 28: 4)
- Centers for Pluralism, 12th meeting (Budapest, Hungary), co-hosted by Civic Initiatives, Serbia, 1998 (Box-folder 28: 5)
- Centers for Pluralism, 13th meeting (Minsk, Belarus), 1999 (Box-folder 28: 6)